# GREG ROQUES FRONT END DEVELOPER

2 Atlanta, GA

504.220.3832

github.com/GregRoques

Greg@GregRoques.com

in linkedin.com/in/GregRoques

## ABOUT ME

I am a former creative director turned software developer with more than 10 years of experience managing award-winning print and online publications. Primarily serving as an editor and art director in my previous roles, I began to witness a sharp shift from the printed page to the more modern digital canvas early in

my career. While serving as creative director for a local magazine, I took the lead in establishing the brand's digital presence. I taught myself as much as I could about UI/Ux to ensure our interface and content best suited our readership, designed initial wireframes for the site, and learned HTML/CSS and basic JavaScript to optimize layouts and functionality within our CMS applications. Thanks to these efforts in collaboration with our development team, our website would quickly become the most awarded digital publication in the city. After several years of pivoting towards digital strategy while continually learning to code, I realized my passion was to dive further into the development of the systems I was directing. I decided to fully dedicate my creative energies towards the design and development of efficient, user-focussed software solutions.

## EXPERIENCE

**Graphic Design 10+ years** (including Creative and Art Direction for print, web and televised media)

Staff and Project Management 9+ years

Digital Marketing 6+ years (social media and web editorial management; use of Google Ads and Analytics and Facebook Ads and Insights)

HTML/CSS 5+ years
JavaScript 3+ years

React, Redux, Express and Node 1+ years

## EDUCATION

Full-Stack Development
DigitalCrafts '19 ~ Atlanta, GA

**Graphic Design**Tulane '10 ~ New Orleans, LA

B.A., Journalism LSU '04 ~ Baton Rouge, LA

## INTERESTS

Distance Running • Photography Learning Spanish • Music

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

www.GregRoques.com/Portfolio

Front End: HMTL/CSS • Bootstrap • JavaScript • jQuery • Angular • React • Redux

**Back End:** Node • Express • MySQL • MongoDB

Graphic Design: Adobe CC: Illustrator • Indesign • Photoshop

# CAREER

**Freelance** Front-End Web Developer/Graphic Designer

June 2019 - present ~ Atlanta, GA (Remote)

• Creating and managing the website and digital marketing strategy for a Miami-based healthcare provider.

### **DigitalCrafts** Developer in Residence

November 2018 - June 2019 ~ Atlanta, GA

• Completed 16-week immersive full-stack engineering program. Following my cohort, I accepted a full-time position as a Developer in Residence working with a course instructor to assist current students with projects and programming concepts.

## American Red Cross Regional Marketing and Communications Manager March 2016 – November 2018 ~ New Orleans, LA

- Direct local digital strategy and serve as a media spokesperson during regional disasters, including the Louisiana August 2016 floods and 2017 and 2018 hurricane season responses.
- Responsible for recruitment, training and retention of Louisiana communications volunteer staff and internship programs across the region.
- Create and teach training courses for regional staff and stakeholders: subjects included serving as a spokesperson, social media management, and digital design and storytelling.
- Design promotional materials and campaigns promoting fundraising and brand exposure.

### Where Y'at Magazine Creative Director

Jan. 2010 - March 2016 ~ New Orleans, LA

- Conceptualized and assigned editorial for print and digital publications.
- Designed print and digital advertisements and editorial layouts.
- Served as the digital director, managing the website, eNewsletter and social media content creation and editorial calendar; experience using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Responsible for staff recruitment, management and retention; this included leading a team of approximately 30 freelancers, interns and editorial managers.
- Led the audience development strategy rebranding the publication to target the city's young professional market. This included redesigning the print publication and overseeing the development of an upgraded website and digital presence.